[{"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8b8", "question": "In what city would you find Boboli Gardens?", "answer": "Florence", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd2d0872596a59cbdfbd37d", "question": "Who said, \" I was really too honest a man to be a politician and live\u201d?", "answer": "Socrates", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be8d", "question": "What measurement was derived from the rope to which a boat's \"chip log\" was tied?", "answer": "The knot", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a80f", "question": "What is the capital of the Canadian province of Saskatchewan?", "answer": "Regina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cae", "question": "What breed of dog is Lassie?", "answer": "Collie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aab9", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Iceland?", "answer": "Gyrfalcon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b92", "question": "What wealthy comic-book title character keeps his mansion tidy with the help of a robot maid, Irona?", "answer": "Richie Rich", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133931f", "question": "In the movie \"Flashdance\", what was Alex Owen's day job?", "answer": "Steel worker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59071c5e3745b36be73039cb", "question": "What is the name of Tony Chu\u2019s daughter in the \"Chew\" comics series?", "answer": "Olive Chu", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133910c", "question": "What nationality was writer, neurologist and psychiatrist Viktor E. Frankl?", "answer": "Austrian", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f53", "question": "Which US actor is the first to star in 8 consecutive number one hit movies?", "answer": "Will Smith", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7d037877e98cb97778a5d", "question": "Louisville, Kentucky sits on what river?", "answer": "Ohio", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b489", "question": "For how many years was the first generation Volkswagen Golf in production?", "answer": "9 years", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8f4", "question": "What do you have if you are suffering from circadian dysrhythmia?", "answer": "Jet lag", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339368", "question": "In the 1960 movie \"Psycho\", what actor plays the private detective?", "answer": "Martin Balsam", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ddc", "question": "Who played the Dark Knight in the movie \"Batman Forever\"?", "answer": "Val Kilmer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa7b", "question": "Harare is the capital of what country?", "answer": "Zimbabwe", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5af259acb63e5727cf5a4851", "question": "Which rock band released the singles \"Karma Police\" and \"Creep\"?", "answer": "Radiohead", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59067ca2ff9c0647b50a806e", "question": "What virtual reality set was launched in March, 2016?", "answer": "Occulus Rift", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fbf", "question": "Who wrote the short novel \"The Old Man and the Sea\"?", "answer": "Ernest Hemingway", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad31", "question": "Elizabeth Bowes-Lyon was better known by what name?", "answer": "The Queen Mother", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fdabd210b8cce1e6fda7061", "question": "What is the body of the DMC DeLorean car made out of?", "answer": "Stainless steel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9b7", "question": "Which Canadian province is immediately east of British Columbia?", "answer": "Alberta", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015ea88fe83fe1f2a824bf1", "question": "What nickname was given to the serial killer, Jack the Ripper?", "answer": "The Whitechapel Murderer", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae00", "question": "Who took 18 days to write the Declaration of Independence?", "answer": "Thomas Jefferson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5b5", "question": "The Golden Gate Bridge is located in what city?", "answer": "San Francisco", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fdabd760b8cce1e6fda7063", "question": "What meat is the primary ingredient in Booyah, a thick stew?", "answer": "Chicken", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6b6", "question": "What company produced the \"Brownie\" camera?", "answer": "Kodak", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b323658bf195a31e15d73ba", "question": "Which James Bond theme was a hit for Sheena Easton?", "answer": "For Your Eyes Only", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff6682f52a821ff76ae8b01", "question": "The last plague that God leveled on the Egyptians was?", "answer": "The last of 12 plagues that Egyptians faced was the death of all first born in the land.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f69", "question": "What do the letters J and D stand for in J. D. Salinger's name?", "answer": "Jerome David", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe6a13620565ad31a57c7a1", "question": "What is the lowest natural point on Earth?", "answer": "The Challenger Deep", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391db", "question": "Who played the godfather in the movie \"The Godfather\"?", "answer": "Marlon Brando", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339683", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is the name of Homer's snow-plowing service?", "answer": "Mr. Plow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b322", "question": "What Asian leader was known as the \"little brown saint\"?", "answer": "Mahatma Gandhi", "category": "history"}, {"id": "597cd75ae347d002c297e4c2", "question": "What is the only continent without native reptiles and snakes?", "answer": "Antarctica", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015f0b4fe83fe1f2a824c12", "question": "At the Seder table, people eat and drink in a reclining position. What does this represent?", "answer": "Freedom", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b42a", "question": "What year did Ian Gillian replace Ronnie James Dio in Black Sabbath?", "answer": "1982", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a04", "question": "What famous model\u2019s last name is Lanzoni?", "answer": "Fabio", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5e9105bbd7247dfc0fa00314", "question": "What is the atomic number of the element Tantalum?", "answer": "73", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af13", "question": "What city hosted the Winter Olympics in 1932?", "answer": "Lake Placid", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd81c98d0de9af39e9d4686", "question": "What U.S. president was nicknamed \"Napoleon of the Stump?\"", "answer": "James K. Polk", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2b5", "question": "Which of Henry VIII's wives may never have slept with him?", "answer": "Anne of Cleves", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339444", "question": "Who played Edward in the movie \"Edward Scissorhands\"?", "answer": "Johnny Depp", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dbc", "question": "In what 1863 short story does Philip Nolan renounce his US citizenship?", "answer": "The Man Without a Country", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c67c", "question": "Bruxism is a medical term for when a person does what?", "answer": "Grinds their teeth", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c711", "question": "What unit of weight is equal to approximately .002 pounds?", "answer": "1 gram", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff2130931a458464a93c44d", "question": "What nationally-observed day in the U.S. marks winter's midpoint?", "answer": "Groundhog Day", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ca8", "question": "What kind of fur coat does Cruella De Vil covet?", "answer": "Dalmatian", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390fe", "question": "Who is the Greek equivalent of the Roman goddess Venus?", "answer": "Aphrodite", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b132", "question": "Who was the leader of Yugoslavia, from 1953 until his death in 1980?", "answer": "Tito", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea3d3dff048f679a45ab49", "question": "Where is the observatory where Percival Lowell first theorized the existence of Pluto?", "answer": "Flagstaff, Arizona", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015ebcafe83fe1f2a824bfa", "question": "What fall festival activity did the Romans bring to Britain when they invaded?", "answer": "Bobbing for apples", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f3b", "question": "What two long-running 1980s TV shows featured characters called Uncle Jesse?", "answer": "The Dukes of Hazzard and Full House", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a05f", "question": "With which singer did Westlife record a version of \"Against all Odds\" in 2000?", "answer": "Mariah Carey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a312", "question": "\"Video Killed the Radio Star\" was the debut music video on which channel in 1981?", "answer": "MTV", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7346aeec85e375820b234", "question": "How many future presidents signed the US Declaration of Independence?", "answer": "Two", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600cc4046de0eb824d4052f0", "question": "In what state is it a law for apple pie to be served with cheese?", "answer": "Vermont -- According to a 1999 law, apple pie must be served with a least one once of cheddar cheese, ice cream or milk", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338928", "question": "Which rock group charted \"Land of Confusion\" in 1986?", "answer": "Genesis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b958", "question": "Who was pictured on the first US adhesive stamp?", "answer": "Benjamin Franklin", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbd2", "question": "How many \"herbs and spices\" does KFC claim to have in their \"secret recipe\"?", "answer": "11", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4b8", "question": "What South American animal is the world's largest rodent?", "answer": "The capybara", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4bc", "question": "Deuteranopia is one of the most common varieties of what condition?", "answer": "Color Blindness", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aff3", "question": "In 1911, what entrepreneur retired as president of Standard Oil?", "answer": "John Davison Rockefeller", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59675ca32b59efe0e9417e95", "question": "The dragonfly has six legs but rarely does what?", "answer": "Walk", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe76bb2eec85e375820b2c7", "question": "Where can you golf the world\u2019s highest elevation championship course?", "answer": "La Paz Golf Club, Bolivia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0a3", "question": "Who is known as Lady Soul?", "answer": "Aretha Franklin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2c6", "question": "Where does vanilla come from?", "answer": "Orchids", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c7e", "question": "What fictional pirate commanded the Jolly Roger?", "answer": "Captain Hook", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9bf", "question": "In which Mega Man game can you acquire the Gemini Laser?", "answer": "Mega Man 3", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c291", "question": "How many equal sides are there on a scalene triangle?", "answer": "None", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c950", "question": "Squid, octopus and cuttlefish are all types of what class?", "answer": "Cephalopod", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c976", "question": "What does an ombrometer measure?", "answer": "Rainfall", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cb06", "question": "When was the Pioneer 10 space probe launched into space?", "answer": "March 2, 1972", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bde6", "question": "What floor number is often skipped in Chinese buildings, as the thirteenth is in the West?", "answer": "Four", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c028", "question": "What does \"shogun\" literally translate to in English?", "answer": "Military commander", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600395cf57a0e35c43f83896", "question": "What is the term for a three-dimensional composition made from a variety of traditionally non-artistic materials and objects?", "answer": "Assemblage", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59049e53cf93664eb10486b3", "question": "The Koson District is a district in the Qashqadaryo Region of which country?", "answer": "Uzbekistan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcab", "question": "What four-letter clarified butter is commonly used in Indian cuisine?", "answer": "Ghee", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b10f", "question": "At what Ohio university were four students shot to death during a 1970 anti-war demonstration?", "answer": "Kent State", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca86", "question": "What culinary ingredient did Hippolyte M\u00e8ge-Mouri\u00e8s invent?", "answer": "Margarine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6010cb0d0775fa611bce6802", "question": "The last leader of the Soviet Union, Mikhail Gorbachev, was in what restaurant commercial?", "answer": "Pizza Hut", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a5", "question": "What is the name of Doc Brown's very clever dog in the \"Back to the Future\" movie franchise?", "answer": "Einstein", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0b1", "question": "What did the band The Clash rock?", "answer": "The Casbah", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fff", "question": "What British TV series featured Saffron and Bubble?", "answer": "Absolutely Fabulous", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd87", "question": "What type of animal is the Japanese monster, Kumonga?", "answer": "Spider", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5ec", "question": "What everyday item did John Walker invent?", "answer": "Friction matches", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2b4", "question": "Who on TV played Jeeves to Hugh Laurie's Bertie Wooster?", "answer": "Stephen Fry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd2d09a2596a59cbdfbd37e", "question": "Who said, \"I don't like that man. I must get to know him better\"?", "answer": "Abraham Lincoln", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fe5", "question": "What actress wrote the autobiography \"Call Me Anna\"?", "answer": "Patty Duke", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afe6", "question": "The US Midwest experienced a severe drought known as the Dust Bowl, during what decade?", "answer": "1930s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d72", "question": "What classic novel's subtitle is \"The Modern Prometheus\"?", "answer": "Frankenstein", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf48", "question": "Transom, poop and keel are all parts of a what?", "answer": "Boat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133beaf", "question": "How many hole cards is each player dealt in Texas Hold 'Em?", "answer": "Two", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394a3", "question": "What was B.J.'s full name in the TV show \"B.J. and the Bear\"?", "answer": "Billie Joe McKay", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cd5", "question": "In folklore, what mysterious ghost ship can never go home and was doomed to sail the oceans forever?", "answer": "The 'Flying Dutchman'", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388b6", "question": "In a 6-string, ordinarily tuned guitar, what are the 6 open notes?", "answer": "EADGBE", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a208", "question": "What is singer Wynonna Judd's real name?", "answer": "Christina Clair Ciminella", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc34", "question": "Which US state is home to CNN?", "answer": "Georgia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba2a", "question": "What boxer was nicknamed the \"Manassa Mauler\"?", "answer": "Jack Dempsey", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe65650ae7e414034b5aec6", "question": "During the Renaissance, Rome had a major rivalry with which city?", "answer": "Florence", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe93d046bd93ce3a4e5f6ae", "question": "Who invented the telescope?", "answer": "Hans Lipperhey (or Lippershey)", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6010cb030775fa611bce6801", "question": "What is the name of a word that is spelled the same forwards and backward?", "answer": "Palindrome", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6ee", "question": "What does \"green lumber\" mean to carpenters?", "answer": "Lumber that is not yet dry", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a15a", "question": "Whose secretary was Loelia Ponsonby?", "answer": "James Bond's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b70a", "question": "According to Irish superstition, what stands open during the 12 days of Christmas?", "answer": "The gates of heaven", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58dba239874c93a3298b2130", "question": "Who wasn't afraid to call James Joyce \"a greasy undergraduate\"?", "answer": "Virginia Wolfe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6012185063c99d48cd169af0", "question": "In Florida, only on Sundays, it is illegal for a single woman to do what?", "answer": "Skydive", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b69f", "question": "What type of berry was once believed to cause birthmarks when eaten by pregnant women?", "answer": "Strawberry", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a52d", "question": "What city is the capital of the US state Idaho?", "answer": "Boise", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe6a4fe20565ad31a57c7c5", "question": "Who was the first sitting US President to throw the first pitch on Opening Day?", "answer": "William Howard Taft", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58d116fb4fea7fe947a22275", "question": "Mickey Mouse is known as what in Italy?", "answer": "Topolino", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c64a", "question": "What does a Scoville unit measure?", "answer": "Spiciness", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5af987cbaeb0982ee4559554", "question": "What Beatles song is referenced in the opening verse to Bad Company's \"Shooting Star\"?", "answer": "Love Me Do", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea80daff048f679a45ac1d", "question": "At what temperature do Fahrenheit and Celsius match?", "answer": "Minus 40 degrees", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd668bba5bfecdd737e0872", "question": "Which religion has the most gods?", "answer": "Hinduism", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601b4b6649076251badbeac4", "question": "Maya Angelou spoke at the inauguration of which U.S. President?", "answer": "Maya Angelou recited her poem \"On the Pulse of Morning,\" at President Bill Clinton's first inauguration in 1993.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59e3f7405cb9e8bda682136e", "question": "What year was the wreck of the Titanic discovered?", "answer": "1985", "category": "history"}, {"id": "60062bb1c9d816e292245c23", "question": "Frida Kahlo was married to which famous muralist?", "answer": "Diego Rivera", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd2cf3e2596a59cbdfbd36d", "question": "Who said, \"There is only one good, knowledge, and one evil, ignorance\"?", "answer": "Socrates", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8dc", "question": "What seven-time NASCAR champion was nickname the \"Intimidator\"?", "answer": "Dale Earnhardt", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b02a", "question": "What ousted Eastern European leader was executed on Christmas Day in 1989?", "answer": "Nicolae Ceausescu", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab38", "question": "Which ocean is Cook Islands located in?", "answer": "Pacific", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c535", "question": "What children's toy started out as wallpaper cleaner?", "answer": "Play-Doh", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b91f", "question": "How many strings does the standard electric guitar have?", "answer": "6", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b323331bf195a31e15d7398", "question": "What is the capital of Botswana?", "answer": "Gaborone", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf1d", "question": "In the nursery rhyme what is Friday's child?", "answer": "Loving and Giving", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a212", "question": "What was the name of the dog in the TV series \"Fraggle Rock\"?", "answer": "Sprocket", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c698", "question": "What constellation represents a hunter with a club and shield?", "answer": "Orion", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe658adae7e414034b5aef5", "question": "Which battle was fought on August 22, 1485?", "answer": "Battle of Bosworth", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5901d90d709c1c34536e6eaa", "question": "In what year did the Ultimate Fighting Championship start?", "answer": "1993", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f9c", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Great Expectations\"?", "answer": "Charles Dickens", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe4ec5506d333868d34d764", "question": "What is the name of the economic program that was created to help Puerto Rico?", "answer": "Operation Bootstrap", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6d4", "question": "What is the atomic number of iodine?", "answer": "53", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ac1", "question": "The book \"The Second Sex\" was written by who?", "answer": "Simone de Beauvoir", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f1f", "question": "What author created Discworld?", "answer": "Terry Pratchett", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3c8", "question": "What is New York City's most popular nickname?", "answer": "The Big Apple", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398cb", "question": "What 1968 movie starred Jack Lemmon and Walter Matthau sharing an apartment?", "answer": "The Odd Couple", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59523dfa736d4be723796b49", "question": "What does the \"Calgary Stampede\" bills itself as?", "answer": "The Greatest Outdoor Show on Earth", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133927c", "question": "What are the only 100% guarantees of safety in the TV show \"Big Brother\"?", "answer": "Head of Household and Veto", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391bf", "question": "How old was Marilyn Monroe when she died?", "answer": "36", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b00e", "question": "What was Lyndon B. Johnson's middle name?", "answer": "Baines", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133925e", "question": "What country was the movie \"Full Metal Jacket\" filmed in?", "answer": "England", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8f8", "question": "What is the fear of microbes known as?", "answer": "Microbiophobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339293", "question": "What 2007 film follows the crew of the Icarus II as they attempt to reignite a falling sun?", "answer": "Sunshine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2c9", "question": "How many feet make a mile?", "answer": "5,280", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff3c2694f032c0db195b481", "question": "How old was Catherine of Aragon when she was betrothed to Prince Arthur?", "answer": "Catherine was three years old", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fdfbfec003d27d341092bda", "question": "What is the largest lake in Alaska?", "answer": "Iliamna Lake", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b643", "question": "In what arcade game did the player attempt to avoid vehicle traffic and crocodiles?", "answer": "Frogger", "category": "general"}, {"id": "592eaefff83302ff91e4648f", "question": "The Pindus is the main mountain range in what country?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ac5", "question": "What quality does a \"rhopalic\" sentence have?", "answer": "Each word has one more letter or syllable than the previous word", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59db78a20ab2c8f322317ff5", "question": "John Downland was an English Renaissance composer for which instrument?", "answer": "The Lute", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a407", "question": "Buffalo Grove is a suburb of what major US city?", "answer": "Chicago", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "601b4c3049076251badbeacf", "question": "Which unique pet did Calvin Coolidge have during his presidency?", "answer": "Raccoon -- Named Rachel, she might be the most well known pet.  She walked around on a leash and was the master of mischief.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea4531ff048f679a45ab91", "question": "What type of muscle bends a joint in the body?", "answer": "Flexor", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5e8a65cc9a45431f553a9cce", "question": "What is the name of the exclusive bar above the \"Pirates of the Caribbean\" within Disneyland?", "answer": "Club 33", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c90f", "question": "What is the only bird that can fly backwards?", "answer": "Hummingbird", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5febac6b7e83c707845b20ed", "question": "How many kilometers are in an astronomical unit?", "answer": "149.6 million", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b14b", "question": "What typewriter key was introduced by Remington in 1878, ending the need for two keys for each letter?", "answer": "Shift key", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b771", "question": "How long is a lane in a bowling alley, measured from the foul line to the head pin?", "answer": "60 feet", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe377f90ada16518afdc04e", "question": "Who was the founder of Cartier?", "answer": "Louis-Frantois Cartier", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b524", "question": "What is Prosciutto?", "answer": "Italian dry-cured ham", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6d6", "question": "What is Canada's popular winter ice sport that is not hockey?", "answer": "Curling", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60077f15bd51d85e222ab63b", "question": "In biology, a relationship between individuals of two species in which one species obtains food or other benefits from the other without either harming or benefiting the latter is called what?", "answer": "Commensalism", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abbe", "question": "What is the capital of Albania?", "answer": "Tirana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "60062bfac9d816e292245c27", "question": "What artist is best known for a painting of his mother?", "answer": "James McNeil Whistler's most famous painting is \"Arrangement in Black and Grey No.1\".  It is commonly known \"Whistler's Mother\".", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe938426bd93ce3a4e5f681", "question": "Iatrophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Doctors", "category": "science"}, {"id": "590722843745b36be7303a00", "question": "How many weeks before Christmas does the 2003 film \"Love Actually\" begin?", "answer": "Five", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338969", "question": "Which 18-year-old married 26-year-old Anne Hathaway in November 1582?", "answer": "William Shakespeare", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcf9", "question": "What was the first nonoriginal color of cereal pieces added to Trix in 1980?", "answer": "Purple", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339651", "question": "What kind of animal is the title character in the 1998 movie \"Paulie\"?", "answer": "Parrot", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d82", "question": "What film's theme song is \"Nothing's Gonna Stop Us Now\", by Starship?", "answer": "Mannequin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c32d", "question": "What does TNT stand for?", "answer": "Trinitrotoluene", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b18f", "question": "The Parthenon in Greece was dedicated to which Greek Goddess?", "answer": "Athena", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7a3", "question": "What mountain chain extends from western Canada down through Northern California?", "answer": "The Cascades", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c0d", "question": "What year was comedian Jon Stewart born?", "answer": "1962", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bae2", "question": "How many candles are on a menorah?", "answer": "9", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e5", "question": "What is known as a \"Magnum Opus\"?", "answer": "The greatest, most popular or most renowned achievement of a writer, artist or composer", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "594d06d21a1c922dd1ac64b0", "question": "What is the oldest bridge over the river Seine in Paris?", "answer": "Pont Neuf", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd88", "question": "What type of animal is the Japanese monster, Manda?", "answer": "Sea serpent", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d07", "question": "What Marvin Hamlisch musical is about dancers auditioning for a musical?", "answer": "A Chorus Line", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd820a0d0de9af39e9d469f", "question": "As of 2020, how many vice presidents have gone on to become president in the US?", "answer": "14", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5be", "question": "Who is the inventor of Coca Cola?", "answer": "John Pemerton", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e42", "question": "What slave name does Kunta Kinte's owner force him to adopt in Alex Haley's \"Roots\"?", "answer": "Toby", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c04f", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Ecuador?", "answer": "Andean condor", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b17", "question": "What was the first name of Julia Roberts' character in the 2001 movie \"Ocean's Eleven\"?", "answer": "Tess", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6ca", "question": "A tree which is deciduous does what?", "answer": "Loses its leaves every year", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f0f", "question": "What actor starred in the movies \"The Forbidden Kingdom\", \"Lethal Weapon 4\", and \"Cradle 2 the Grave\"?", "answer": "Jet Li", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c62b86e0ae4aacefc17eee1", "question": "What was Studio Ghibli's highest grossing film?", "answer": "Spirited Away", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdc0c99469bb8041d07a053", "question": "What type of horse is named from the Spanish word meaning \"painted\"?", "answer": "Pinto", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfb2", "question": "Macrophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Long waits", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c5b", "question": "What weather phenomenon swept Dorothy Gale to the Land of Oz?", "answer": "A tornado", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc68", "question": "What college did Brett Favre attend and play football for?", "answer": "Southern Mississippi", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cbe", "question": "What fairytale girl eats the window pane of the witch's cottage?", "answer": "Gretel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c06e", "question": "In what decade was Montreal Canadien great Guy Lafleur born?", "answer": "1950s", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fec84c6ec223966ae8f8802", "question": "In 1985, Patrick Ewing was the first No. 1 pick under what system?", "answer": "The draft lottery", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133918d", "question": "Which is the only one of the Seven Dwarfs without a beard?", "answer": "Dopey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ae865ac7f28483af1e7fdd1", "question": "In 2018, a meme featured what Sonic character with a Ugandan accent saying: \"Do you know the way?\"", "answer": "Knuckles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea7b2cff048f679a45abf3", "question": "What arctic sea whale has one long horn on its head?", "answer": "Narwhal", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7d2", "question": "What is the English translation of the area of Cuba called Bahia de Cochinos?", "answer": "Bay of Pigs", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acc6", "question": "What was the ultimate destination for most travelers of the Underground Railroad?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339367", "question": "What model car did Thelma and Louise drive?", "answer": "Ford Thunderbird", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fa9", "question": "The Empire State Building went dark for 15 minutes to mark the August 2004 death of what actress?", "answer": "Fay Wray", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd663a0a5bfecdd737e0852", "question": "How long does it take blood to circulate the vascular system?", "answer": "20 seconds", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58dba70f874c93a3298b2160", "question": "What is Peter Chriss\u2019 persona name in the band KISS?", "answer": "The Catman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b15c", "question": "Who was awarded the Nobel Peace Prize in 1979?", "answer": "Mother Teresa", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58f1678af7c52aae91cc07ba", "question": "What year did the Republic of Guinea-Bissau declare independance from Portugal?", "answer": "1973", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c688", "question": "Who took a leave of absence in the mid 1940's from his position at Cal Tech to direct the Manhattan Project?", "answer": "Robert Oppenheimer", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b7ffb3b3a3a814d89068c63", "question": "Who is considered the Father of English literature?", "answer": "Geoffrey Chaucer", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921c", "question": "What city did the band U2 form in?", "answer": "Dublin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5be57d5e5415ba52ed6f0aa6", "question": "How many minutes are in a day?", "answer": "1,440", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdfb", "question": "How many enemy planes must a pilot shoot down to be called an ace?", "answer": "Five", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339423", "question": "What basketball player starred alongside Jean Claude Van Damme in the movie \"Double Team\"?", "answer": "Dennis Rodman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c449", "question": "How many chromosomes does a horse have?", "answer": "64", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7db", "question": "In which US state is the headquarters for the Mayo Clinic?", "answer": "Minnesota", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca8a", "question": "Goitre is mostly caused by the lack of what element in the diet?", "answer": "Iodine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59008f4fcf842fa4c4ba96ba", "question": "Who released the 1970 album \"After the Gold Rush\"?", "answer": "Neil Young", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef66606ce05a3942286e78", "question": "What was Scrabble originally called?", "answer": "Lexico", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a466", "question": "In what state would you find the Black Rock Desert?", "answer": "Nevada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab15", "question": "What US state includes the telephone area code 515?", "answer": "Iowa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1b8", "question": "In 2005, Bhutan became the first country to entirely ban what?", "answer": "Tobacco", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ace", "question": "In the novel \"Don Quixote\", what swiveling structures are mistaken for giants?", "answer": "Windmills", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9da", "question": "How many dots are on a Pac-Man board?", "answer": "240", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd2d7db2596a59cbdfbd3bb", "question": "What American folk hero was a real-life Tennessee congressman?", "answer": "Davy Crockett", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bda5", "question": "What is the name for the arrow-like projectiles fired by a crossbow?", "answer": "Bolts", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5d1", "question": "How did Norman E. Shumway make medical history?", "answer": "He performed the first successful transplant", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338997", "question": "Which American author's most famous novel was \"Myra Breckinridge\"?", "answer": "Gore VIdal", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae08", "question": "Which New England state was an independent republic for 14 years before joining the union?", "answer": "Vermont", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133906a", "question": "Which American poet also practiced medicine?", "answer": "Oliver Wendell Holmes Sr.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd968bc23c87fd04dd15e03", "question": "What was the name of the first electronic computer?", "answer": "ENIAC", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a94b", "question": "Prior to August 1984, Burkina Faso was known by what name?", "answer": "The Republic of Upper Volta", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e5c", "question": "Who provided the original voice for Marge Simpson?", "answer": "Julie Kavner", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b090", "question": "In 1983, the first Disney theme park built outside the US opened in what country?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a701", "question": "Which US state is home to the Inyo Mountains?", "answer": "California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd66029a5bfecdd737e0831", "question": "What percentage of Americans believe in Astrology", "answer": "26", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133917f", "question": "Who is the Kindergarten Cop?", "answer": "Arnold Schwarzenneger", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015e763fe83fe1f2a824bd2", "question": "Although never taking her seat, who was the first woman to be elected to the houses of parliament in Europe?", "answer": "Countess Markievicz", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cb05", "question": "What year was the Pioneer 10 space probe launched into space?", "answer": "1972", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339764", "question": "What is the name of the Warden in Chicago?", "answer": "Matron 'Mama' Morton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4bd", "question": "What part of the eye changes shape in LASIK surgery?", "answer": "The cornea", "category": "science"}, {"id": "597742ee284458f1d7854423", "question": "What \"America's Got Talent\" host replaced Nick Cannon?", "answer": "Tyra Banks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5921fc96a4edfd43a087adc0", "question": "Sweet Baby Broccoli is another name for what vegetable?", "answer": "Broccolini", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a07a", "question": "What film won the oscar for best visual effects In 1984?", "answer": "Indiana Jones and the Temple of Doom", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aeac", "question": "Who was the second president of the United States?", "answer": "John Adams", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339221", "question": "Which two artists formed the band \"Wham!\"?", "answer": "George Michael and Andrew Ridgeley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c780", "question": "Part of Dr. Eugene Shoemaker's ashes are buried at what unique place?", "answer": "The Moon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339895", "question": "The line \"Greed, for a lack of better word, is good!\" can be heard in what movie?", "answer": "Wall Street", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a79d", "question": "Pearl Harbor is located on which Hawaiian island?", "answer": "Oahu", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5efa96f2ccb363a2cbc5227d", "question": "How many people helped direct the 2019 season of \"The Mandalorian\"?", "answer": "5", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe1f341145fb29466707399", "question": "What candy bar originally came in three pieces and had three different flavors?", "answer": "3 Musketeers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b211", "question": "Who was assassinated by Gavrilo Princip?", "answer": "Archduke Ferdinand", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a39c", "question": "What is the fifth largest country in the world?", "answer": "Brazil", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396e8", "question": "In what city is Jim Morrison buried?", "answer": "Paris", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395f7", "question": "In The Simpsons episode, \"Treehouse of Horror V,\" what does Homer turn into a time machine?", "answer": "A toaster", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ebd", "question": "What Broadway musical featured the song \"Chicago\"?", "answer": "Pal Joey", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffa3fdec73aa70ea0b70b04", "question": "Which U.S state's motto is \"Industry\"?", "answer": "Utah", "category": "geography"}]